Bret Petersen

Full Stack Web Developer

Minneapolis, MN 55404 (willing to relocate) • 415.939.1779 • <u>bretpetersen@gmail.com</u> <u>bretpetersen.com</u> • <u>linkedin.com/in/bret-petersen/</u> • <u>github.com/bretpeters3n</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience in visual design who enjoys the fast-paced environment of the tech industry and being part of pioneering teams. React-fluent developer who enjoys creating interaction and animation filled mobile and desktop experiences.

Core Competencies and Skills: Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for React.js.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React.js, Node.js, Javascript, jQuery, Express, SQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Responsive Design, ORM, MVC, ES6, Git, Unit Testing, Snapshot Testing, CSS, and HTML.

PROJECTS

True Crime Quiz

Served as project lead while developing an application allowing users to test their true crime knowledge. *Tools used:* React.js, Framer Motion, Auth0, Bootstrap, Javascript, Mongo Atlas and Heroku.

https://aithub.com/bretpeters3n/true-crime-quiz • https://true-crime-quiz.herokuapp.com

Cat Memory

Acted as project lead in developing an application allowing users to play a game of memory with cat photos. *Tools used:* Javascript, Bootstrap, the Cat API, and GitHub Pages.

https://github.com/bretpeters3n/cat-memory • https://bretpeters3n.github.io/cat-memory

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer • Irish Titan, St. Louis Park, MN

03/2020 - 06/2021

- Communicated with clients to discover their needs and fine tune their projects.
- Researched and tested e-commerce apps for use on our client's online stores.

Key achievement: Expedited adoption of Figma as the main software design tool.

Web Specialist • United Healthcare, Hopkins, MN

08/2019 - 12/2019

- Animated advertisements and designed emails.
- Helped usher in more efficient email coding with the use of templates.

Key achievement: Received 'Employee of the Month' honor.

Web Animator • Target, Minneapolis, MN

07/2018 - 02/2019

- Created animated advertisements while working alongside a team of designers and developers.
- Introduced 3D animation into advertisements to increase their noticeability.

Key achievement: Facilitated faster workflow using Hype as main animation software.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate • University of Minnesota

Fall 2021

UX Certificate • Brainco (Minneapolis, MN)

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design • University of Minnesota Duluth